<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>STM32F7 on AllThingsEmbedded</title><link>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/tags/stm32f7/</link><description>Recent content in STM32F7 on AllThingsEmbedded</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 18:23:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/tags/stm32f7/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bootloaders and ARM Cortex-M microcontrollers: Booting the target application</title><link>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/post/2019-10-12-bootloaders-and-arm-cortex-m-microcontrollers-booting-the-target-application/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2019 18:23:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/post/2019-10-12-bootloaders-and-arm-cortex-m-microcontrollers-booting-the-target-application/</guid><description>In a previous blog we discussed the role of the NVIC in ARM Cortex-M microcontrollers. This peripheral will play a central role in booting our target application. First of all, we need to discuss the boot process in an ARM Cortex-M microcontroller.
Boot process After Power On Reset the microcontroller assumes the NVIC table is located at address 0x00000000. The processor fetches the first two words in the NVIC table, corresponding to the top of the stack and the reset vector.</description></item><item><title>Bootloaders and ARM Cortex-M microcontrollers: Design</title><link>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/post/2019-05-31-bootloaders-and-arm-cortex-m-microcontrollers-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 15:37:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/post/2019-05-31-bootloaders-and-arm-cortex-m-microcontrollers-design/</guid><description>Welcome to the second entry of the Bootloader series! Today we are going to be discussing the design and basic architecture of the bootloader application.
As we talked about on the last post, we are not going to be using any libraries, other than the C++ standard library in order to maximize portability and performance and limit code bloat. This means that we will be writing our own Hardware Abstraction Layer for all the peripherals and core features of the bootloader.</description></item><item><title>Bootloaders and ARM Cortex-M microcontrollers (STM32F7): Introduction</title><link>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/post/2019-05-19-bootloaders-and-arm-cortex-m-microcontrollers-stm32f7-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 17:23:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://allthingsembedded.com/staging-web/post/2019-05-19-bootloaders-and-arm-cortex-m-microcontrollers-stm32f7-introduction/</guid><description>We are introducing a new series to the blog, containing all about bootloaders for small ARM Cortex-M microcontrollers. I hope you like it.
What is a bootloader? A bootloader is a piece of firmware that takes care of booting the target application, as well as providing a mechanism to update the firmware on the field, where you don&amp;rsquo;t have the means to flash the device using more advanced hardware interfaces such as JTAG, SWD or ICSP.</description></item></channel></rss>